can you buy
[Music]
the title of my message today
is
and I want you to look at your neighbor
when I announced this title and say it
to them
and say it like you believe it everyone
can succeed
even you
look at your other neighbor and say
everyone can succeed
even you
said John 2
in the King James version reads beloved
I wish above all things that
you may prosper and be in hell
even as your soul prospers
God wants us to prosper
some translations say success or succeed
God says I wish above all things that
you
God wants you to succeed
and in this scripture God is telling us
that success
is not what belongs to a select elect
group
there are no people who were born with
the advantage of succeeding
yes we understand that
our environments and our contexts are
not the same but even then
it doesn't mean if you are born in a
right environment you will succeed
nor does it mean if you were born in a
difficult environment you will not
succeed
God says I wish above all things
that you may prosper and be in hell
tell your neighbor again you can succeed
tell your other neighbor you can succeed
tell your other neighbor you will
succeed
in the name of the Lord Jesus Christ
thank you
but then I want us to go to Genesis
chapter 4
and I'm just reading a portion of it and
I'll narrate the story later
as you go along just the first part of
verse 7 just a portion of it this is
when God is talking to Cain
's problem was that
he couldn't take it when he's so Abel
succeeding
because
much as we all want to succeed what we
need to also understand is Success
brings enemies
there are people who don't want to see
you succeeding
sometimes people are okay
and all of a sudden they change
but they change at the time when your
life starts changing and becoming better
and Cain had a problem
because he couldn't just take it
that his brother was succeeding and not
him and God says to him in verse 7 just
the portion of it in the NIV Bible he
says if you do what is right
will you not be accepted in other words
if you do what's right will you not also
share in the same success
because he's not succeeding because he
is God's favorite he's succeeding
because of the things that he does
if you do what's right success is not
what handed to you
success you can't blame it on somebody
else that I'm like this because of them
I know you feel better to blame
but it's not going to take you anywhere
to blame others
because even if everybody is against you
and if everybody says things will never
work through you if you will do certain
things
you can apply certain principles
you will succeed
in the new English translation verse 6
and 7 it says then the Lord said to Cain
why are you angry
and why is your expression done cursed
it's not true that if you do what is
right you'll be fine
but if you don't do what's right sin is
crouching at the door
because you see
it takes a mature person to celebrate
somebody else's success
more so if you are all born in the same
place same time same church same
everything same environment same
background same qasi Mara this one is
succeeding I'm not succeeding
so maybe I'd rather come up with
just come up with something
just come up with something then credit
it to their decision making
then eat Humble Pie and say they were
willing to do what I was willing to do
what I was not willing to do
they were willing to pay the price when
I didn't pay the price God says if you
will do what's right
you would do what right
the complete Jewish Bible says if you're
doing what is good shouldn't you hold
your head high
and if you don't do what's good sin is
crouching at the door
it wants you
Mara you can rule over it in other words
look jealousy says no don't congratulate
it but don't allow jealousy to control
you congratulate them even if you don't
feel like it
come on now don't give a painful
clapping of hands let it be a joyous one
come on now everybody
The Message Bible says God spoke to Cain
why this tantrum why the subtle King
if you do well won't you be accepted
God's saying look there's no sacred
formula to success
and there are no chosen people who were
predestined to succeed
is available to all
because other one plus one one plus one
is true for everybody it doesn't matter
how old you are how young you are what
color of skin you are one plus one is
two
it's gonna work for everybody
tell your neighbor you can succeed too
so here's the interesting thing in
Barcelona
hardwired into the core of you
that which God has programmed on the
inside of you is the desire to succeed
unfortunately some of you you've allowed
that to die
you've allowed failure to become your
friend and your pattern
you've you've you've married yourself to
being mediocre
you've convinced yourself that you can
always explain things
even if you're underperforming
look at the neighbor Say Amen
everybody wants to succeed look at
children
when they start achieving their
milestones
you can almost see once a child starts
achieving something they want to do more
there's just something in them they just
want to get better they just want to
push themselves why has that died in you
some of you you've allowed the
disappointments of life
and the many failures to blow out that
candle you know I often say this and
this is what I always say I say you know
when they were telling me about you
Kairos people
and I was so happy to hear that I said
I'm so glad they're so passionate
because you know what I found out
you know what I found out I'd rather
have a passionate person
who's on Overdrive
for God
then have to go and vuselah somebody
I found out of experience it's very hard
to light up the fire of God that has
died in somebody
their candle is gone
no fire no passion
the light is gone
I would rather have somebody or Papa
do you understand what I'm saying I'd
rather have a church
because it's easy to cure the treasure
Darkness
than to cure passivity
oh yeah
oh yeah some of you you've allowed that
fire that desire
that God encoding
that God programming
that you had when you were a child
you've allowed it to die because you've
had so many failures
but if you just
bear with me for a while can I tell you
something the road to success is
littered with a lot of failures on the
path
anybody who has ever succeeded will tell
you
a lot of stories in fact we'll talk
about it Lima Bishop the other day you
know it struck me the other day that a
lot of people have made a lot of money
have also lost a lot of money
he's a billionaire who has lost Millions
my others have lost my rather still a
millionaire
so if you want your journey to be nice
and not have problems you're not going
to suck and you'll be afraid of success
because the minute you put your path on
the path of success you are going to be
a target for the enemy
he's going to beat you up he's going to
make sure people are jealous he's going
to make sure people say all kinds of
things he's going to create problems
he's going to attack you with sickness
and disease he's going to take your
resources away from you he's going to
make your friends turn away from you
he's going to make your family walk away
from you he's going to make everything
just don't work out
but the thing is how hard do you want it
how desperate are you
everyone can succeed
everybody wants to succeed
see success is the plan of God for
Humanity
but from the scriptures we've read it
comes when we do what is right by God's
standard
because you see there's there's success
by World standards that we call success
God doesn't call success
I like the Book of Joshua when God was
speaking to Joshua and he qualifies it
he says this book of the Lord shall not
be part out of your mouth
he says but thou shall meditate there in
day and night occurring that you may
observe to do
success comes from the doing
not from the watching and the talking
and the whatever from the dude that you
may observe to do according to all that
is written there in he says for then
there's always a then with success
you can spend years and years and years
doing what's right and never seeing any
success making the right decisions doing
the things but there Comes a Day move
only break through I see breakthrough in
your life in Jesus
dreamed of the day when we will have
many pastors Sent From Grace Bible
Church
I've looked forward because you see in
the early days of ministry and I wasn't
doing it for people God spoke to me
about releasing people in the church but
you know when you
when you don't understand you she said
people
in Trent they're not even ready
so they want to manipulate you
into doing things the wrong way when
they're not ready you must send them out
you're right guitar
all right
if you want to succeed you must have the
patience to stay the course and to do
what's right over the Long Haul because
there's always a then
this book of the law shall not depart
out of your mouth but Thou shalt
meditate the in day and night that you
may observe to do according to all all
all all that's written the info then
Thou shalt make thy way
thou shall make thy Way Prosper us and
then Thou shalt have good success note
What God Says didn't say I'll make you
successful says you will make your way
prosperous
then let me explain God says now already
I'm going to make you successful it
depends if you're going to work it
it's up to you God says I I leave the
ball in your court
he says thou shall have good success and
I like the way he qualifies it because
there's good success and there's bad
success
see you know well people think money
means success
as important as money is man doesn't
mean success
because you can have a lot of money and
not have peace in your heart
buy the most expensive bed and suffer
from insomnia
have the most beautiful house that has a
lot of tension in it
no peace every day
marry the most beautiful woman the most
handsome guy who cheats on you
foreign
[Applause]
good success is you love Jesus with all
your heart yourself God with all your
heart there's peace in your heart
there's peace in your home doesn't mean
you don't have problems
at the same time
[Applause]
to Define your life no you use it you
don't pray to it you use it you pray to
God Mariah now you use it
because God says sit me with all your
heart
seeketh us the kingdom of God and his
righteousness and are all these things
shall be
a good success
somebody shot Hallelujah in the house
that's good success
yeah nothing as nice as you're living in
a house you know you don't have to be
afraid for it
because
you're serving at a job come and saying
you don't have to pay anybody a cat
[Applause]
somebody say good success
by doing the right things
we need to become successful God's way
measure success by God's standard which
are the following number one
success is doing what God has assigned
you to do now this you'll find very
strange
and then in practice Jeremiah
when you do what God has assigned you to
do there's no way where God
promises you that the path is going to
be easy
and when you read the Bible
when God comes and makes you account
for your assignment
he
he checks how Faithfully you weigh
he's not too much concerned about the
outcome
you didn't get me
mama
if God says this is what I want you to
do
this is how I want you to do it God
expects you to do it and what God looks
for is faithfulness
now you know sometimes you can be
faithful and never get the outcome it
might be a journey where every day you
are caught in problems in challenges you
never have peace even one day in your
life and yet you are doing God's will
we've never talked about that
fatalities
Jeremiah
young Prophet very impressionable
God asks a question
I need someone okay who can Ascend he
raises I said me me I like young people
I like that passion
yeah papa but I love it
I like people who feel they can make a
difference I like them because I want
their passion I know they're naive but I
want their passion
foreign
Primary School when the teacher asked a
question and everyone's like me
do that and that says all right I'm
sending you to the children of Israel
but and God says to him born don't don't
don't look at their faces
because Jeremiah is Young and naive he
thinks oh why must I wear so I'm
passionate
why does it matter
you know it's almost like when you are
canceling a a couple personally you know
and I used to do counseling back then
and I'm sitting with them and I'm
counseling them about marriage and I can
see about Mamel
chemistry
because Bachelor was a baby baby
in their hearts
me and you baby we will never fight
me and you our love is so big it's so
thick it's so strong we are here
so they are just coming fella
because they don't value what you're
telling them
because they're young they are naive
and then three months later Bishop
look at universe
so Jeremiah is like that he says to God
me me me me and God says Okay God so he
goes and you must go read the whole book
of Jeremiah the first few chapters he
throws himself at the work of God
I mean this guy he wants the people he
preaches his heart out he talks to them
and he's expecting them to repent
instead of repenting they revolt
they take him they beat him they throw
him into boiling oil they throw him into
a hall I mean they just stepped and they
studied there in a shock say oh God you
didn't tell me
because when God tells you he doesn't
tell you how the path will turn out
and Jeremiah
come back to God and now they are having
a first session
foreign
but the problem is when a call has come
on your life you can't walk away from it
[Applause]
when God has pointed his finger at your
direction even if what you are involved
in involves your life and takes your
life away from it you can't sleep at
night you can't walk away from it and
Jeremiah says all right God get high up
I'll go back
I'll go back he goes the second time
they do the same third time third time
he gets to be very very very very very
very very very depressed
and he starts cursing everything
says cast be the day on which I was born
he has to be the hospital when the kids
be the nurse
and can't be the guy who came out with
the cigar to announce it's a boy cast be
him
and he because it's everything and you
can see the guy's depressed but then
this tone changes after a while
and then he goes
it's not where we get that song
he says even if I I'm in trouble even if
it's not working out the way I am I can
feel God's love all around me
like some of you we have to take care of
an ungrateful family of an ungrateful
people then you don't know why you do it
you don't want to do it but you are
still doing it anyhow and you can't walk
away from it even if you feel bruised
you still go back and help them after
you said I will never go back again
but you don't understand why you are
doing it
you're doing it because it's not just
what you're doing there's a call on the
inside of you and God has given you the
assignment
and God's assignment is not always easy
when you have to preach to the same
people who criticize you and write
stories about you the same people who
say evil things about you and you stand
there and you tell them you love them
even when you can see hate in their eyes
the call of God
calls us to serve on a higher level and
Jeremiah says he says a steadfast love
of the Lord never ceases
and then he goes on he says God's
message on you every morning what is he
saying he's saying you know what I've
learned now I'll just take it one day at
a time
because this assignment drains me it
takes away everything on the inside of
me I'll get enough power for one day and
for that day I will throw myself into
what God has told me and I'll go to bed
and I will recoup I will recharge and
when I wake up I wake up with new
strength and new anointed to do God's
will
because it's not about how good it is
it's about how faithful I am
some of you have difficult assignments
you are leading a company of cruel
people
you are in a difficult position in your
family you are the anchor in the family
but everybody beats on you
and by the word standard you think
you're not succeeding
Maria you are succeeding
because you're faithful to the mission
come on somebody give the Lord a shot
come on somebody give them another shark
oh God I pray for people whose hearts
are broken in this house
and those who are watching who have a
difficult assignment right now
I pray that your spirit will rest on
them
and that you will strengthen them for
another day
and I will wake up knowing fully well
that the steadfast love of the Lord
never ceases
and your message never come to an end in
fact your mercies are new every morning
and great is your faithfulness oh God
I pray you'll know that
that's my prayer for you
and instead of checking how much money
you made
or how happy you are how much you smile
and how much you loved
some of the assignments we don't even
laugh
just get busy with it
because a day comes when God will reward
you for it
when you stand before him and God will
say
you raised autistic children
couldn't talk
to you couldn't respond you raise
children couldn't walk couldn't do this
and you're locked in the home
you saw your friends
walking around freely doing everything
freely to you it was like it's a prison
house
but you are faithful
Jason
some of you you are you are upholding
those families everybody in the family
who useless
I'm sorry to say it like that
they don't want to come to the party
you are the burden Bearer
and they don't even have the decency to
say thank you
listen
it's not about that thank you
it's about what the master will say when
you stand before him
oh come on somebody give the Lord a hand
come on Grace Bible Church Give the Lord
a hand
come on give the Lord a hand let the
Lord Empower you today in your spirit
so
God's way of measuring success is
faithfulness to the assignment secondly
God's way of measuring success is what
you do with the gifts he's given you
in Matthew 25 we hear the parable of
Jesus when he talks about the master who
came
and called his servants to come and give
a reckoning in an account
some of you you are not using the gifts
God's given you sitting on them
they're sitting on them
you don't use it at church you don't use
it at work
your career path doesn't line up with
your gifts and your talents
and the Bible says there comes a day
when God's going to ask you what did you
do
what did you do with the teaching gift I
gave you what did you do with the
leadership gift I gave you
what did you do with the ability to sing
that I gave you what did you do with the
gift of Mercy I gave you
what did you do with the gift of
administrations that I imparted to you
what did you do with those gifts
so here we go
we need to then avoid the Trap that Cain
fell into
Cain became jealous because he wasn't
applying himself
his personality got all twisted because
he felt that it's not fair that Abel is
successful now I'm not successful it's
not because God has anything against you
God says if you will do what's right
so let's avoid the Trap of Cain
number one the Trap
of failure to understand our different
god-given capacities
even when we succeed we don't succeed at
the same capacity
read the Bible God always allots
when Jethro advised Moses says no have
leaders who will be leaders of thousands
leaders of hundreds leaders of tense he
said there are those that God's given
capacity to lead thousands
let's come back to the faithfulness
question
the our problem is we measure ourselves
by looking at what others do are doing
and comparing ourselves with them
he says I want to apprehend what Christ
has apprehended for me what it means is
this I'm going to only stand next to the
picture yeah what God wants me to look
like because there'll always be somebody
who does better than me there'll always
be somebody who does worse than me
if I stand next to the one who does
better than me and their capacity is
more I'll feel like a failure if I stand
next to one who has less capacity than
me I'll be elevated in false Pride
because I think I'm doing better but I
want to challenge myself and stand next
to Christ and say Christ how am I doing
when it comes to my assignment
how do I compare with what you said I
must do
so we fall into that type of cane a
because we fail to understand our
different god-given capacities B we fall
into the Trap of being irritated when we
see the grace of God upon somebody
helping them to succeed
you really have to be mature to
celebrate somebody's success
you really have to be matured
Joseph's brothers they loved him until
he dreamed
Saul was okay with David until David
killed Goliath
there's just something about success
that brings enemies
so avoid that trap of being irritated
when you see your brother your sister
succeed learn to congratulate them
because your turn will come too
yeah
when you see somebody under the
spotlight
and have they are apart don't spoil the
party
you may never be in the spotlight but
God will do something for you
because just like the body there are
certain parts of our body that are not
meant
to be exposed
huh
you know you know when people see you
they say you have such a beautiful you
have such beautiful eyes
I was able to see that you know I
noticed during lockdown every people's
eyes are beautiful
you've got beautiful eyes I never ever
remember somebody said you have a
beautiful liver
you have a beautiful spleen
I don't ever remember myself you have a
beautiful but he has a funny part if
it's out your eye
it's not fatal to you
if you were to take out your liver you
couldn't live
so it's funny that the Unseen part is
more vital
uh
I'm just saying not everybody is meant
to be under the spotlight
be where God has placed you
if you are the lever of the body be the
liver and make sure that the whole body
stays alive because of you
even if nobody knows your name
be delivered
can I hear a good amen
avoid the Trap of bitterness
you know the people who live who are
bitter in life oh Peter Peter Peter they
are not moving on in their life because
they are bitter they remember what their
uncle said to them when they were five
years old now the guy is 50 years old
but he still talks about it like it
happened yesterday
we if we all wanted to be bitter we can
us has ever been immune to bad things
being done to you and where you could be
justified to dislike and to be bitter
if I wanted I could be bitter with many
of you here in the church
you know like I'm telling you in the
next day it will be 40 years being a
pastor of Grace Bible Church by the
grace of God
yes I've had speakers
[Music]
[Applause]
hmm
if you will allow what they do and what
they say to get to you
and I'm thinking you're going to walk
away from God because of people
that's stupid
you you're gonna block your whole
spiritual Destiny because of people
are you telling me when you're going to
walk away you're going to walk away from
a great future
because of a human being
God never told they said that we are
perfect
and I add we all just differ in the
degree of Googling
others Gula more than others but so in
case
we all look beautiful
oh Jesus
oh Baba
nice
hold on
we all look good
but get them when they're off key
[Applause]
so what must we do we must love
must forgive
get rid of bitterness
there's nobody who's ever succeeded in
life who doesn't have a sad story to
tell
nobody
so I know you're going to let your sad
story be your handicap
you want to say to us that the reason
you are not moving on is because your
uncle said to you when you're five years
old woman and you're 50 years old now
you want me to buy that
[Music]
really you you feel good
are you going to sacrifice your whole
Destiny by holding on to bitterness
that's what we're gonna do
oh no
if you want to succeed you must just
understand this road in America
you have to decide to walk through it
sometimes you don't even stop to talk to
the people who's hurting you you just
leave them and just move on because they
don't understand where you are going
oh come on give me the Lord a big hand
let me let me close with this uh but I
feel later next week sermon but I'm not
close with this
I want to suggest this thing
if you want to succeed commit yourself
to a journey
of self-development
commit yourself go to Just
a challenge
and say as for me
I refuse
to be mediocre
as for me but I'm telling you you have
to have a certain way of
way often than your thinking
refuse to allow your mind to tell you
that you're a nobody and you'll never go
anywhere just live away what your uncle
told you in your five years just start
thinking differently get the challenge
and I'm gonna put my success is not
anybody's burden but my burden
I'm not going to wait for people to do
things for me I'm going to get up and do
it for myself
so I'm not going to rule my letter I
don't even know repeal again
but I'm gonna do it myself tell your
neighbor oti challenge
invest in your personal development why
because everybody wins when you get
better
and if you're already successful
remember whatever level of success you
are or growth you are you can still get
better
we could stop with having several
branches in this one Church aquatic I'm
thinking thousand churches and when we
get a thousand I have a Temptation that
I probably would say two thousand three
thousand not one stop
because the God we serve doesn't know
the word enough
he's more than enough
this comes into my spirit now the more
you grow
is the more you realize is doable
and it's the more Your Capacity becomes
more
particularly if you become faithful
it says about Jesus in Luke chapter 2
verse 52 and Jesus increased somebody
say increased tell you never you need to
increase
tell your other neighbor you need to
increase tell your neighbor neighbor I
want to increase
that would increase means watch this
it means to advance
it means to grow in time
it means to profit
to proceed
Jesus increased
increase such as process increase
suggest movement
he moved from one step to the other from
one place to the other in other words
when you came back after a year he was
not in the same spot some of you are
still in the same spot
you haven't done something you haven't
applied anything you haven't challenged
yourself ever since you've got a degree
A1
challenge yourself
somebody say increase
it says Jesus increased but it increased
in these three areas in the first
service I couldn't cover the three I
might not cover the three year I might
just cover the one it has increased in
wisdom oh my goodness
in stature number two
and in favor with God and man
so Jesus increased in three areas he put
himself on a success trajectory
he put himself on a path
to get better
so when he says he increased in wisdom
the word wisdom there is the Greek word
Sofia
and not what Sophia is the word
translated wisdom now here's what I find
interesting with that word that word
doesn't mean having a lot of learning
or having a lot of book knowledge
or technical skills
but what it means it means having the
ability
to know how to live life in a practical
way
because there are many people who may
have the qualification but they don't
know how to live life in a practical way
they can't handle their money
they can handle their time
they've got a certificate
which is important that we must have
but that's not all there is to it
they don't know how to live in wisdom
this is what wisdom speaks about the
ability to cope with the situations of
life
where you know how to cope with money
relationships how to lead people how to
deal with spiritual issues moral issues
there are people who you know their
moral life they don't understand it
doesn't make sense he's drinking
something he knows he's killing him and
he can give you a thesis on the danger
of what he's drinking my life drinking
it
that's not wisdom
God give us the wisdom and the good
thing Barcelona is wisdom helps us to
make good decisions in life
it helps us to make good decisions in
Ministry you know I was sharing with
them in the first service in our clothes
with that example that you know
I thank God for what my dad did to me
when I started working
thank God you know raising a good home
as you've heard me say all of that and
and my dad when I started working
uh this is 1982. it it yeah end of 81.
and you know I wanted to get married you
know
so he called me said
I said yeah papa and I want to get
married he said all right
now that you're working I'm advising you
you know
open a separate bank account and save
money
because you're going to get married I'm
young you know I'm impressionable I'm
not wise
I have a gold man I don't know how to
get there
anybody who knows what I'm talking about
so the first year
I blew it
was
even though I must say to my credit I
spend most of it buying cassettes and
books which wasn't bad
you know
but I didn't save up any money as I
should at least in kohai which wasn't a
lot of money I paid for my own
schooling you know a bible school I paid
the fees and on my own transport and
whatever
and at the first year
yeah so a year later my dad calls me and
says
a year ago
we we had a meeting this is a follow-up
meeting we want to see the outcomes
where's the bank book
how many of you know
some of you young ones you start blaming
the weather you start blaming your
upbringing you start blaming everyone
and that day the penny dropped
that day wisdom entered my mind and I
realized you know it's really not about
the amount of money you have
is about knowing how to use it wisely
if you don't spend more than what you
have you'll have money and if you don't
spend on what is not necessary you will
have money
money so I uh
when the trains were still working and
then I I I would buy
you know brown bread and
and milk and and I bought
into your peanut butter and and cheese
coffee
so I'd make this coffee and go to work
and I saw my peers my age group like me
they didn't have wisdom at the time they
were eating exactly what I was eating
they had the same needs I was having but
they hadn't changed their mind they
hadn't increased in wisdom
so they spent their money during lunch
time to impress others Baraka you
wouldn't understand I used to call it
it's a hamburger
I tell you
when I looked at how my home Burger cost
why they paid for one home Burger on one
day is the same amount I would pay to
buy a whole month's supply for my lunch
yeah peanut butter
ing
I was using wisdom
time later I had money to get married
and then I could buy more things and
soon I learned you know when it comes to
money it's just how you use it thank God
we're to God merriately mama mama had
the same wisdom and we decided with
it with when we got married we don't ask
we are done in my
imagine a church of 2000 people I wasn't
earning much money so regardless
we tried to buy a house cost over to we
didn't qualify for a bond we didn't have
enough money so we went to a back room
Church
the problem with some of us we like to
impress people
so that will label will live from head
to toe
but the problem is
or you want to buy a car credit card
credit card and then you have to pay
interest
I just cannot understand
foreign
listen carefully
from then we decided Mama we're gonna
save money we're going to buy our then
there's an opportunity came for a place
in a place called Loli
they had houses there that they were
building we couldn't afford a house in
Soweto and then lowly lowly one
and the house was costing 45 000 rents
when money was still money
but during the time we had stayed there
in a room
a lot we didn't have kids we didn't have
many responsibilities
and we saved up money we had a good
amount of deposit for the house
so instead of taking a bondia 45 000 I
think we took one year twenty five
thousand if I don't remember if I
remember we put down 20 000 something
like that
and then we decided to pay off that 45
000 in record time sold the house for 80
000. took that money put it somewhere
and I was like let me tell you what I'm
telling you
all of that wisdom
we put it into running the church here
right here
yeah
and we land it's really not about
because some of you you earn a lot of
money
you do you
I guess everywhere I get like um
especially next to these two guys here
Mario in debt up to here
why
because regular Ferrari
you are living in a gated community
all the time regular cell phone earlier
6000 units here please call me every
time
and you're living to impress people when
at the end of the month you slip into
depression
but you're not increasing in wisdom
and because you can't run your financial
life properly you are not able to handle
it when they give you a lot of money
somewhere else because
you have to learn
certain things can wait certain things
I'll afford them later
you can't be 24 years and uboso to drive
a Ferrari
unless oh you are a child of a very rich
person but normally only 24 you are
broke
how many of you are 24 years and you're
same WhatsApp group like me my girl
don't worry
next
you're hoping hurry she's an independent
because
[Applause]
I finally got an amen from my young
pastors here Jesus but what am I saying
tell your neighbor increase
say it again
put yourself in a path of development
increase in the ability to handle life
has a way to be lived
you look at our parents howdy how
with no education Nation know anything
not earning a lot of money raising five
children seven children eight children
we all eight we all had clothes here we
are here today how did they do it they
couldn't even read
how did they do it
wisdom
yeah wisdom but then I'm telling you
it's the same principles in running a
church you see people think fella if you
know I have this whatever whatever
there's wisdom in running a church
there's wisdom in running a home there's
wisdom in running a business that's why
you see some other person their business
is thriving
I was listening to somebody the other
day who was telling me they were asking
them or his particular government I
won't tell you which one it is why don't
they bank account loan because what they
have in terms of their total amount they
are challenging
it's enough for them to be able to
finance certain programs and they found
out I don't know it was a complex thing
they're explaining some of you finance
people will know that I couldn't
understand it but I got a bit of it if
they were to use the money they have
they would have to repay much more so
it's cheaper for them to get a loan
because in that loan they get a form of
rebate
said go far alone so it doesn't mean
when you borrow money you are wrong just
means just weigh your options
have wisdom
I see the wisdom of God on my life
I said I see the wisdom of God on your
life
Jesus increased and put himself on a
path of growth would you bow your hairs
please and close your eyes Right Where
You Are
Hallelujah
our hair is about our eyes closed some
of you have been invited in this place
some of you have come on your own some
of you it's your first time
even in the places where we are live
streaming
maybe it's not even your first time but
as you've been listening to the word
you realize that Jesus is the only one
who can bring change
and transformation in your life
you can't change your life In Your Own
Strength
in your own power
our own human wisdom our own human ways
fails to change and transform us you're
here you're in the Church there you're
live streaming yes you've been listening
to God's word you realize that God's the
only one
who can change your life I want to pray
for you
I want to pray for you to receive Christ
as Savior and Lord maybe for the first
time maybe you want to recommit your
life to God maybe you lived for God and
somewhere around the line you
you kind of fell off and
slipped into other things and and now as
you've been listening to God's word you
realize God's the only one who can
change you our head's bowed please our
eyes closed if you fit in any of those
categories and you say please pray for
me
I really need God's help would you
please pray for me would you raise your
hand right where you are just raise it
high let me see it I want to pray for
you just raise it high thank you for
those hands I so appreciate people who
raise their hands without fear without
doubting they just raise their hand like
that thank you
just raise it up where you are you don't
need to be afraid this is the place
where God changes lives
this is the place where God Specializes
in transforming lives and changing
Destinies and putting your life on a
different path
I asked the people who raise their hands
would you please just stand on your feet
right where you are you can put your
hands down but just stand on your feet
please right where you are just stand if
you raise your hand just stand right by
you I want to pray for you thank you
thank you thank you thank you thank you
thank you thank you this is what it's
about
this is what it's about if you're
sitting next to somebody
sitting there just find out from them
are you really saved do you really know
Christ do you understand just talk to
them now just find out do you understand
some of them might be afraid to stand
and just tell them no I'll stand with
you I'll stand with you and just help
them if you've brought a friend say man
I'll stand with you you want to receive
Christ just then just go ahead and stand
all over this place just stand all over
just stand stand with them thank you at
the back God bless you stand with them
don't let them stand alone stand with
them we know you are safe but we're not
Emma Lebon I just stand with them stand
with them say I'll join you in this this
is an important decision today God bless
you God bless you
Hallelujah all right I want to invite
all of you who are standing even those
of you who are standing with your friend
I'm going to ask you to come with them I
want to pray for all of you all right
can you just walk from where you are
take your belongings don't leave your
belongings behind all right take all
your belongings just walk all the way
there I just will help you come stand
here and we will pray
[Music]